# **EUGEN RUPI**

# GRADUATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER

# **PROFILE**

A self-motivated software engineer who is eager to work and contribute to a successful team. I have been involved with programming for the past 10 years and am looking forward to apply my skills and work in a field I really enjoy and feel passionate about.

## CONTACT

+44 777 4768 980

eugen.rupi23@gmail.com

ni linkedin.com/in/eugenrupi

## **PROJECTS**

#### 1. Heart Game Project

A project for a video game using Java and external 3<sup>rd</sup> parties API from multiple platforms.

#### 2. OCR - Text Detection Editor

Built with ElectronJS using OCR Technology to detect text from images.

#### 3. TikTacToe Game

A TicTakToe Game made using C# and WinForms. View Project

#### 4. Elevator Simulation Project

An Elevator simulation software built with C#, which also includes a Database. View Project

## **OTHER**

# 5. Transmission Propagation Delay Calculator

A small program developed using C, which can calculate the transmission and propagation delay of the given router/routers. View Project

#### 6. Device Vendor Finder

An application that can find all connected devices and show their MAC-Vendors. View Project

#### **EDUCATION**

#### **University of Bedfordshire**

2019 - 2022

Bachelor of Science (with Honours) - BSc (Hons) in Software Engineering.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# The Glasses Company LTD – Customer Adviser & Administrator 2021 – 2022 (Currently)

Responsible for updating customers and managing orders. Developed a Browser Extension using JavaScript, to help automate order updates for the customers in order to minimize "human error". Also developed a new Google Sheets Template to manage orders more efficiently using AppScript. And finally, created a new MySQL database for storing different tool settings and user data from the clients.

#### Self Employed - Web & Browser Extension Developer

September 2021 - December 2021

Worked with a team of developers remotely, to create a new framework called Saffron, which allows applications to get content from articles on different websites automatically by scraping the website only once, manually.

#### Volunteer Work – Web Developer

2016 - 2017

Helped develop a new website for my school as a volunteer. The languages used to develop the website were HTML, CSS, JavaScript for the Front-End and PHP for the Back-End, and the WordPress theme.

#### **SKILLS**

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- **Programming Languages:** Java, Python, JavaScript, PHP, C#, Visual Basic, C.
- Other Languages: HTML, CSS, XML, JSON.
- **Frameworks:** React, React-Native, NodeJS, ElectronJS.
- **Databases:** MySQL.
- Version Control: Git-Bash (GitHub).

# **SOFT SKILLS**

- Time management.
- Excellent communication skills.
- Problem-solving.
- Analytical skills.
- Teamwork.

#### LANGUAGES

- **English** Professional working proficiency.
- Albanian Native or Bilingual Proficiency.
- Greek Native or Bilingual Proficiency.